## ANUJ BUNKAR

http://anujbunkar.com

anujbunkar97@gmail.com | +1 813-947-9181

#### **SUMMARY**

Outcome driven professional, master's in business analytics, 5+ years of working experience with data analysis & data visualization tools, such as SQL, Excel & Tableau, to support decision-making and provide insights to stakeholders. Available to join immediately.

### **EDUCATION**

### W. P. Carey School of Business at Arizona State University

August 2022 - May 2023

Master of Science in Business Analytics (MSBA) With Distinction

Tempe, AZ

- CGPA: 4.0/4.0
- Relevant Coursework: Enterprise Analytics, Data Mining, Statistics, Data-Driven Quality Management, Analytical Decision Modeling, Advanced Marketing Analytics, Text Mining, Deep Learning

### **Indian Institute of Technology Madras**

August 2015 – May 2019

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech), Chemical Engineering | CGPA: 3.0/4.0

Chennai, India

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: SQL (SQLite, MYSQL), Python (Pandas, NumPy, Sci-Kit Learn, Matplotlib, Plotly), HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Analytics Tools: Microsoft Excel, Google Spreadsheet, SPSS, Minitab, JMP, Tableau, Power BI, Looker Studio, QlikView, Cognos, SAS Analytics, Google Analytics, Google Big Query, Snowflake, MATLAB, SAP, Redash, Metabase
- Data Analytics: Data Warehousing, ETL, Database Management, Data Visualization, Statistical Modeling, Machine Learning
- Others: Git, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform, Microsoft Azure, Apache Spark, Google OAuth, A/B testing

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Business Analyst – Revenue & Pricing Operations**

June 2023 - Present

Houston, TX

Sears Home Services

- Automated NLA process using web scraping & APIs, saved 400+ man-hours & enhanced efficiency with one stop dashboard
- Built Tableau dashboard to track 2M+ in-home parts, enabled cost analysis, price trends, and automated P&L-impact alerts
- Optimized job mapping by integrating labor cost and decline data, reducing misclassifications, adding \$100K monthly revenue
- Designed a P&L reporting framework & savings tracker for Amazon parts pilot, validating \$1M in projected annual savings
- Launched A/B tests for D2C pricing, driving a \$200K monthly revenue increase by analyzing revenue, profit and repair rates
- Developed a Tableau dashboard aggregating field performance metrics, enabling real-time monitoring for field teams nationwide
- Conducted random audits of B2B claims, identified discrepancies & uncovered four recurring issues, saved \$100K monthly loss

Led strategic pricing for 50K in-home parts based on cost, competitor & margin analysis, conducted A/B testing to drive profitability

# **Business Analyst – Strategy & Business Operations**

May 2019 - May 2022

Bengaluru, India

UrbanPiper Technology

- Utilized advanced excel modeling approach for accurately forecasting annual targets for revenue & cost centric functions
- Prepared strategic budget plan, distilled a \$5 Million budget for regional & functional teams, aligned with projected targets
- Led companywide OKR process, aligned teams via effective communication, fostering seamless collaboration & resolving disputes among teams, ensuring 100% efficiency across all functions
- Revamped sales strategy and created specific plans for each region, closely monitoring revenue realization and creating dashboards on Looker Studio for management and sales leaders to review progress, resulting in a massive 45% jump in sales
- Collaborated with customer success leadership to set up weekly reports, analyze customer success executives' KPIs and deployed strategies resulting in a reduction of churn by 5% and an increase of CSAT by 80%
- Spearheaded monthly exercises to report P&L Visibility, Runway Management and Management Information System

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# Automobile Pricing Analysis and Predictive Modeling, WP Carey School of Business

August 2022

- Conducted EDA on large automotive dataset, formed a linear regression model to foresee MSRP with R-Squared of 83%
- Unveiled significant revelation of Engine Fuel Type being most sensitive feature to MSRP, with diesel cars having highest average MSRP of \$41K, offering makers valuable insight to adjust pricing strategies for diesel models to maximize profit

### Flight Delay Prediction using Machine Learning, W.P. Carey School of Business

October 2022

- Developed a ML model to predict flight delays using logistic regression & KNN, resulting in a model accuracy of 81%
- Performed a cost-benefit analysis to select best probability threshold balancing false positive and false negative cases to optimize customer experience and minimize costs for the airline
- Deployed model online using Streamlit to improve customer experience by providing accurate flight status updates